RESIDENT PLAYBOOK
EPISODE 1
BP is dropping.
BP is 80 over 60. Heart rate is 130.
Respiration is 30.
Start another line
in the other arm for fluid loading.
- Yes, sir.
- Sir!
Sir, open your eyes! Are you awake?
Sir, can you hear me?
Okay, let's move him.
One, two, three!
Sir, do you know where you are?
Could you try opening your eyes?
BP is dropping.
Starting CPR.
What's going on?
TA patient, with mental status stupor,
went into arrest,
so I'm performing CPR.
- Open him up.
- Here?
It'll be a table death
if we don't do it now.
Open him up. Hurry.
Wait. Me?
- But I'm just an intern--
- Get it together!
If we don't stop the internal bleeding,
he won't survive.
Don't you know that?
Don't just stand there! Do it now!
We'll perform simultaneous surgeries.
I'll lower the intracranial pressure.
Dr. Oh, perform cardiac massage
directly with your hands.
But I don't even have gloves on.
Does that matter right now?
That's not what's important.
Then what is important?
What's important is…
You gave up being a doctor.
You quit.
You're
not a doctor anymore.
You gave up being a doctor.
You quit.
You're not even a doctor.
What are you even doing here?
Oh Yi-young, you're not a doctor.
- Ms. Oh?
- Dr. Oh.
- Dr. Oh!
Ms. Oh?
Are you okay?
You must've been dreaming.
Yes, it was a nightmare.
Oh, dear.
Geez, I just had to dream
something like that…
I'm never going back.
If I ever do, it'll be over my dead body.
This premium package
is only for our VIP clients.
We'll finish the massage
with this gold-infused natural oil.
Okay.
How much is this though?
It's the package you've always chosen.
How much was it again?
A hundred?
One… one million won?
Since you added foot care today,
it's 1.2 million.
Hold on.
That's strange. I should be broke.
Come on. I know you're not.
But my dad went
totally bankrupt last year.
Come on.
You must still have a little bit left.
I doubt it. I likely maxed out
my overdraft account too.
I see.
You spent it all.
So you have no money.
Then you won't have any money
either today, tomorrow, or in the future?
That's right.
Then you give me no choice.
Sorry?
If you don't have money,
you'll have to work it off.
That's how the world works.
Hold on.
What is this? Don't! Stop!
In this world,
there are things you have to do
even if you don't want to, Dr. Oh.
For example, earning money.
No, I have money. I do…
Really! I do have money!
No. You don't.
All right. Shall we start
with the kidneys?
- Music.
- Yes, ma'am.
No! Stop!
Stop…
No. Wait.
Not the saw.
Hello?
I'm driving right now.
What was that? Could you repeat…
Ms. Oh Yi-young.
You're currently using
our bank's overdraft account.
It looks like your due date is next week.
We've tried to contact you several times,
but you must've been very busy.
Yes.
A little bit.
I see. Currently,
you can either repay
the overdraft amount of 50 million won
- or--
- Wait.
I used up all 50 million?
The total balance
is negative 46,407,000 won, ma'am.
If immediate repayment is difficult,
you can extend the loan period.
Then I'll do that.
All right, ma'am.
If you bring your certificate
of employment by next week--
I don't have one.
Then what about your previous year's
tax withholding statement?
I don't have that either.
Do you have a job at the moment?
Then, when do you plan on working again?
It's not that I don't want to work.
I just can't.
I tried.
But I don't think
the working environment suits me.
It's too hard.
So it doesn't suit you.
Then, in that case…
Once the due date passes,
and depending on the credit card company,
your card may be suspended
and your limit may be reduced.
As creditor,
the bank may request the courts
for an investigation of assets.
Then assets could be frozen.
And after that, there may be legal action
and seizure of assets, ma'am.
What did you say I needed again?
- A certificate…
- A certificate?
…of employment.
Of employment.
A certificate of employment.
RESIDENT PLAYBOOK
What's taking you so long?
You're going out like that?
Joo-young, these pants are latest--
Right. They're nice.
We'll be late. Let's go.
By the way…
Do I really have to go?
Damn it.
JONGNO YULJE MEDICAL CENTER
At least it feels familiar
since you interned here, right?
I guess.
At least we won't get lost.
Let go of me. I'm not a child.
This isn't my first rodeo.
I need to see you go inside
with my own eyes.
You're smart, so I know you'll do well.
You'll find it fulfilling
and make money too.
Right, you'll even be able
to make friends. How great is that?
Whatever.
Who was it that scammed Dad again?
A friend of 50 years
who stole five billion won.
Good. I'm glad you brought it up.
He's not the only one who went broke.
You did too. You're dirt-poor.
You have no home or car.
Just debts. So shut it.
Still, it's embarrassing
to come back here.
Use your brain for once, will you?
He can't open a hospital for you anymore.
You can't be a director.
And what hospital would take you
after that huge mess you made?
You think you can go to any university
or local hospital there is?
That's why I'm back here.
If it weren't for me, you would've missed
applying for the additional recruitment.
You should be thanking me.
All right.
I'll go in.
Geez.
Just hang in there
until you repay the 50 million won.
After that…
Whatever! We'll talk again
after you pay it back.
You quit before repaying your debt,
and you'll be lying in the morgue.
Got that?
Geez, I can't stand looking at you.
Get in there!
Bye.
You little…
Just one year.
Please just hang in there for one year.
Just a moment!
Wait!
- Going up.
- Thank you.
- We're getting off.
- Excuse me.
It's so nice to see you here.
Sure.
The lounge moved
to the fifth floor last year.
Please pretend you don't know me.
I was just letting you know
since you seemed unaware.
As a fourth-year to a first-year.
You can tell the other first-years.
Don't tell me anything.
It's weirder
that you're making such a fuss.
All right.
Don't complain I didn't help later.
That's never going to happen.
No, to your right.
RESIDENT LOUNGE
AUTHORIZED PERSONNEL ONLY
Yes, I'm on my way.
OB-GYN, FIRST-YEAR RESIDENT LOUNGE
2023 OB-GYN RESIDENT RECRUITMENT
- Good morning.
- Hello.
Hi.
You all look so different
in your lab coats.
Take a seat.
Thank you.
I'm a fourth-year resident, Ku Do-won.
This is third-year resident,
Dr. Ki Eun-mi.
This is second-year resident,
Dr. Cha Da-hye.
They'll be your saviors today.
Say hi.
Hi, guys.
Today's your first day,
so let's do introductions.
What?
Wow, is this real?
It's ancient history, but--
The top student is joining our department?
Which "top" were you referring to?
I was top student in med school
and got the top score on national exams.
I'm Kim Sa-bi.
I read Prof. Seo Jung-min's paper
on "Pre-eclampsia Prediction Algorithm
Using Machine Learning" last March
and became interested
in the OB-GYN department.
And last month, after I read her paper
on "Pregnancy Complications
and Fetal Programming in the Uterus,"
that cemented my decision.
I look forward to working with you.
You're better than your seniors.
She published another paper?
- Beats me.
- Next up…
This has to be a real first.
That's right. It's not common.
You two attended the same high school?
Did you know each other?
We both went to Baejin High School.
Nam-jeong?
Nam-kyung.
Right, Nam-kyung.
We were classmates in junior year.
Classmates in senior year.
You're right. Sorry.
Jung Nam-kyung?
Pyo Nam-kyung.
Dr. Pyo, it looks like you stopped
dying your hair halfway through.
Why? Did you run out of money? Or time?
This is the trend.
If I untie it,
you can't see the dyed part.
So when the professors are around,
I'll keep my hair down.
When they're not, I'll have it tied.
Different styles?
You'll be quite busy.
Okay, introduce yourself.
Hello, I'm Pyo Nam-kyung.
I may look like an uptight city slicker,
but I'm actually pretty easygoing.
I hope we can all get along well.
- All right.
- Thank you.
Next…
Dr. Oh Yi-young.
I'm Oh Yi-young. I'm 28 years old.
That's it.
The thing about Dr. Oh is…
She interned and started
her residency here two years ago,
and then went to a local hospital.
Simply put,
she's repeating a year as a resident.
- I see.
Well, she's back now.
That's what matters, right?
You're all in the same year,
so try to get along. Okay?
And lastly…
Yes, it's me.
Dr. Um, your coat is inside out.
No one usually makes that mistake.
- Right.
- Introduce yourself first.
Hello! I'm Um Jae-il,
and I'm 28 years old.
My stage name is Um Jay.
Stage name? Why a stage name?
"Umji"?
Like in the Korean phrase for "thumbs up"?
No. It's Um Jay.
Um. J-A-Y.
- He's our first foreigner, right?
- Yes.
I'm not a foreigner.
- What?
- I'm like a one-hit wonder.
From an old music group.
- I was in an old K-pop idol group--
- That's right!
Cha Eun-woo's group.
No, not that one.
No, it's that actor. What was his name?
- Yim Si-wan. His group.
- Oh, that.
No, not ZE:A either.
We were called HI-BOYZ.
We did this.
Right! You might've seen this one.
Basically, you're saying
you used to be a K-pop idol?
Fine. Say something quick
and wrap it up. I'm busy.
Yes, sir.
I might not be the best at studying,
but I'm good at physical work.
I'll keep going
until the soles of my feet wear out.
I'd appreciate your support.
All right.
Anyways, we're glad you're all here.
Let's give them a hand!
Clap, clap.
Since it's your first day,
our senior residents
will help you a lot today.
But since they're also busy,
let's not ask the same questions
or make the same mistakes twice.
Yes, sir!
But always ask if you don't know something
and check things that are unclear.
- Yes, sir!
- Yes, sir.
If your mistake comes all the way to me,
it means you messed up big time.
So let's hope we don't meet again today.
- Got it?
- Yes, sir!
- Dismissed.
- Dismissed!
Good luck.
Have a nice day.
Goodbye.
I'm heading up to the Gynecology ward.
Good luck.
Right, I have to go to the ward too.
See you later.
Hello.
Hey, I'm a bit disappointed though.
We were the top two students
at Baejin High.
We were archrivals.
We were?
I guess not.
You don't believe what our classmates said
about me following you
to med school, do you?
That's news to me.
- The operating room?
- Yeah.
- Whose surgery?
- Prof. Seo Jung-min's.
Yikes. Surgery on your first day
with Seo Jung-min?
Don't you remember? You interned here.
No, I don't remember.
Hey, I'll let you in on something
since we're old classmates.
They say a notorious endemic disease
is going around here.
The "Bitchy Disease."
Seo Jung-min's terminal.
She tears you down with her words
and eyes over and over again.
- She's that scary?
- Yeah.
If you get on her bad side,
she'll criticize you all day.
She's out to torment us.
You know what her nickname is?
Hello.
So we have a new first-year resident.
Welcome.
Did our junior resident watch
the surgery videos in advance?
I did.
Just your luck
to get me on your first day.
Did you hear that my nickname is
- "The Witch"?
- Yes.
Who told you?
First-year resident Pyo Nam-kyung.
What a helpful colleague she is.
By the way, junior. Isn't your vision
blurry and hazy right now?
- It is.
- You can't see in front of you
and things look out of focus?
Yes, how did you…
How did you know that?
Right? I wonder how.
Ma'am.
Right.
Thank you.
Ma'am, she's been contaminated.
We need to deliver the baby quickly
since it's general anesthesia.
We'll make the incision
right after intubation.
Dr. First-Year.
Pay close attention.
Yes, ma'am.
I'll start the time-out checklist.
Can the anesthesiologist
verify the patient?
Yes, registration number 19210681.
Patient name, Sung Hui-young.
- Diagnosis and procedure?
- Placenta previa totalis.
A low flap transverse cesarean section
will be performed.
- Do we have fetal cord blood sampling?
- No.
- Is everything correct?
- Yes.
- Beginning anesthesia.
- Okay.
SURGERY IN PROGRESS
Richardson retractor.
Meyer forceps.
Pull. One, two, three.
Bladder retractor.
Metzenbaum.
Scalpel.
I'll apply fundal pressure.
APPLYING PRESSURE
ON THE TOP OF THE UTERUS
The baby is out.
Hi!
Time is 10:23 a.m. It's a baby girl.
- Is the baby okay?
- Yes, Apgar score is nine.
Saturation level is good,
and her pulse is over 100.
Hey, junior.
You used two pairs
of gloves on your first day.
What a busy day, right?
Do-won, I'll leave the rest to you.
Yes, ma'am.
- Good work, everyone.
- Thank you.
Was her name Oh Yi-young?
The one who caused trouble
at a local hospital?
Yeah, that's her.
I felt bad for her though.
She had Prof. Seo on her first day.
I think she's already on her bad side.
Geez, what awful luck.
That's just her fate.
And the surgery's over now, right?
That's just how you pass the days.
It's not over.
We're packed with OB surgeries today.
But seriously, what'll she do?
Isn't it obvious? She'll have to bear it.
Make way! She's in labor! Move aside!
Slow down. You're going too fast.
No, hurry up! Quick!
The baby's coming!
Hello?
I'll come up right away.
Where have you been?
Here.
You're the first.
All right.
"I wish you happiness."
I was checking
Mr. Yoon I-sang's biopsy result.
I see.
What is this?
My autograph.
You better not sell that online.
Dr. Um, it's a busy day today.
We don't have time to joke around.
These are Cho Seon-yeong's test results.
And you can check
biopsy results on your computer.
You don't have to ask in person.
I was curious about the result.
I thought I could get it faster in person,
but it wasn't out yet.
No way. Jay's a doctor?
I knew it.
He's just as smart as he is sexy.
Doctor.
Yes, hello.
Hello.
I was told to exercise a lot
after the surgery,
so I've been walking around.
But for some reason,
my chest feels uncomfortable
and my shoulder hurts.
Is this normal?
Could you tell me your name?
Yoon Jung-sun.
My shoulder's been hurting
since this morning.
How should I describe it? My chest
feels tight.
Your shoulder and chest area feel stiff.
And you feel short of breath too?
Yes, that's right.
Is this normal after surgeries?
One moment, please.
Hello, Dr. Cha.
I'm sorry to call you for the fifth time.
I think I found
a case of aortic dissection.
What? What did you say?
A tear in the aorta.
I'm coming now.
- Did she get a chest CT scan?
- Right, a CT scan.
Have you gotten a chest CT scan?
What's that?
Hold on. Who are you talking to right now?
The patient is standing
in front of me right now.
An aortic dissection patient
is standing in front of you?
Yes, she's here right now.
Dr. Um.
Yes, Doctor?
Are you kidding me right now?!
Unbelievable!
FIRST-YEAR
I think being lazy might be better.
He's too eager for his own good.
Isn't that a good thing?
He's always busy.
He meets with patients,
asks questions, and takes notes.
Then he does it over and over again.
But he never gets anything right.
We were also like him once.
Don't you remember last March?
- I don't think I was like that.
- Yeah, you were. I'm a witness.
Still, I'm sure he has
at least one good quality.
He's hard-working.
And his flaw?
This too shall pass.
Summer will be here in a flash.
FIRST-YEAR
What is it now, Dr. Um?
So,
we won't know until we have the surgery?
Yes.
If you look at Section 2-1
of the procedure explanation,
after incising the skin,
we'll assess the extent of the illness
in the abdominal cavity and determine
which organs need to be removed.
I see.
Doctor.
It's…
it's not that difficult
of a surgery, is it?
If we find cancer during surgery,
the extent of the surgery may increase.
Excuse me.
Surgery will take 4 to 5 hours
according to textbooks
with approximately
a 30% chance of complications.
Could you please sign here?
I'm sorry.
I caught you right at mealtime.
Enjoy your dinner.
AUTHORIZED PERSONNEL ONLY
Is that too little? Want more?
No, thanks.
The line's long. Keep moving forward.
Spinach?
Go. Grilled short rib patties?
- Five, please.
- Five…
Really?
- Bean sprouts?
- Three.
- Tofu.
- One?
At least you got a meal break
between surgeries today.
Consider yourself lucky.
Eat up.
What time do we get off today?
At this rate…
Gosh, not on time.
Damn it.
Why do we come to work on time
but never leave on time?
Make sure you eat up.
She's bleeding.
What are you doing, junior?
- Kleenex.
- Kleenex?
What's the English word again?
Tissue, please.
There are no tissues
in the operating room. It's gauze.
You're too relaxed for your first day.
I'm sorry.
Cut.
Is that a souvenir?
Throw it away.
Do I have to tell you that too?
Junior, why put it there
when you can throw it away?
What hospital taught you to put it there?
- At Jongno Yulje--
- Hey!
Objects could end up in the patient
if you leave them in the surgical field!
Get rid of it now!
I'll hold it tight
and throw it away later outside.
Take the suture and leave right now.
Get out of the field right now!
Damn it.
I never said you could move.
I told you to stand there
and watch carefully.
- I have eyes in the back of my head.
- Yes, ma'am.
Cut.
Damn it.
Excuse me, Dr. Cha.
Knock, knock. Sorry to bother you.
Come in. What is it now?
I just checked
on patient Lee Suk-ja in Room 1014.
And?
Her BP is normal.
And the JP drain?
I'll go check again.
Sure. Off you go.
Excuse me, Dr. Cha.
Knock, knock.
Back already?
It was just across the hall.
The JP drain has minimal drainage
and the color looks fine.
Okay. Good work.
Dr. Cha.
Patient Kim Min-suk in Room 1012
has clear fluid leaking from her nose.
Post-surgery,
she's had a headache but no fever.
But clear fluid is leaking from her nose.
So?
So perhaps…
Perhaps?
…it's a skull fracture?
First, an aortic dissection.
And now, a skull fracture?
Yes, at least that's what I think it is.
Ms. Kim had surgery yesterday,
so she's been lying in bed all day.
So how could she have
possibly injured her head?
How? Where?
Why?
I can't tell you that,
but a skull fracture can cause
cerebrospinal fluid to leak from the nose.
I learned that in med school.
So I've been checking
her nasal discharge every 30 minutes.
- Dr. Um.
- Yes?
I wasn't going to say this, but…
Don't you ever get
a runny nose?
- I do.
- You do, right?
We all get it from time to time.
I do. You do.
- Ju-yeon?
- Yes?
- Do you get a runny nose?
- I do.
See? Everyone does.
Patients get it.
Doctors get it. Nurses get it.
All of humanity gets runny noses!
For crying out loud!
Are you okay, ma'am?
I'm monitoring you carefully.
Doctor.
You'll have a safe delivery, ma'am.
It's okay. You can count on me.
That's not it.
Sorry?
You're the one
who doesn't seem to be okay.
I'm just really scared too.
I'm sorry.
That was Pyo Nam-kyung, right?
Yeah, I think so.
Where are you headed?
To get this surgical consent form signed.
Among current residents, I think I may be
the best at getting them signed.
Good for you.
Are you saying you won't sign it?
I won't sign it.
Take it back.
Then would you like
to sign it a little later?
I don't want to receive surgery.
But you need to get it.
You need to sign this right now.
Doctor.
May I ask you something?
You doctors are so smart.
There's a bunch of difficult words
written on that consent form,
yet you memorize them all
to explain them to us
and answer any questions we have.
So I have a question.
Why was I…
cursed with this terrible illness?
Sorry?
You see…
I never drank
or smoked.
And I've tried to live
a good, decent life.
I was afraid of getting punished.
So,
why has this happened to me
for the second time now?
Well…
If I knew the reason,
at least I wouldn't feel so wronged.
So, what's the reason? Doctor?
Being a good person
and… cancer recurrence
aren't related.
I see.
Hey! Good news!
A blind date?
Wrong.
This is even better news.
Better? What is it?
Professor Seo
gave us her credit card.
- Why?
- She said, for working hard today,
we can treat ourselves to good food.
What should we eat? What do you want?
I have dinner plans. Sorry.
See you tomorrow. Bye.
Hey, who has dinner plans this late?
I need to return a book.
Let's eat next time.
Isn't that your book?
Where are you returning…
I'm not hungry.
Enjoy the food.
I can't eat alone.
- Let's eat together next time then.
- Okay.
Good luck.
You should've asked.
I could've driven you.
Prof. Seo is always sensitive
on surgery days.
She doesn't mean anything bad by it,
so I hope you understand.
No, just bear it.
You must be very tired.
No hospital talk at home.
All right.
Why do we have to
keep it secret at work that we're…
Is our relationship weird?
What's so weird?
What good would come of it if they knew?
I could quit at any time.
I doubt it'll be anytime soon.
You're wrong.
I could quit tomorrow if I want.
I doubt it.
God! Stop being so annoying.
Geez, you startled me.
Are you serious?
I didn't do anything.
That's my foot, you know?
It wasn't me.
It was a mouse.
- I heard mice are everywhere these days.
- Really? No wonder.
Here, honey.
Have all the expensive things
before your sister
and this fool eat it all.
You should eat up too.
Just watching you eat
is good enough for me.
Seung-won.
Get your heart checked out
at a hospital as soon as possible.
You have to be sick
to still be in love like that.
Hey, I told you
to speak respectfully to him.
Seung-won is older than you, okay?
Don't take your anger out on him.
Do-won, where are your table manners?
Why did you kick her?
You're making Yi-young uncomfortable.
I'm sorry. I guess it was me.
Just consider this
a way of earning your keep.
Do-won, how was she today?
Did she do well?
Did she cause any trouble?
No, she did fine.
She did well.
So today,
in the operating room, Joo-young--
Don't.
Okay.
What happened?
The professor told her
to throw away a piece of suture,
but she didn't know where to put it.
So she went like this, and then--
I told you to stop.
She worked hard.
Don't tell me…
She already fell out of favor
with the professor?
- She can't quit anytime soon.
- Says who?
You can pay back 50 million that quickly?
Is 50 million a joke to you?
Also, you should've spent less
if you didn't have any money.
But you splurged left and right
without any thought.
Ever since you started spending
so recklessly, I saw this coming.
Even if you gave the bank
your entire monthly paycheck,
you'd need to work a year
to pay the principal.
Come to your senses, you brat.
Damn it.
You didn't have to
tell them about my debt.
I'm not eating.
Geez. Do-won, have some hairtail.
If it weren't for Do-won,
you would've never gotten
into such a big hospital.
You told me
about the shortage of applicants.
While we were eating,
I only said our department was short
and was accepting extra applicants.
I didn't know you'd apply though.
I really didn't think you'd get in.
This is all abuse of power,
school ties, and regional ties.
Everything bad.
What power do I have?
If running my mouth over dinner
counts as power…
Does it count?
What school or regional ties do you have?
Who do you think you are?
It was just good timing.
You only got in thanks to your abilities.
Don't baby her.
That's how she ended up like this.
Who babied me?
Mom and Dad.
And who else? No one.
Grandma. Our aunts and uncle.
There are tons!
Ku Do-won speaking.
You're handing over Ms. Eun Sang-mi to me?
Okay. I'll come right away.
Do-won, at least finish your meal.
I need to go to the hospital.
Again?
A fellow on vacation asked for a favor.
Here.
Dr. Oh, I hope to see you tomorrow.
Gosh.
He can't even eat in peace.
I don't think he's slept well in days.
I told you this job wasn't worth it.
Geez, you little…
Check the lab results on the EMR.
You see that monitor?
Monitor the baby's heart rate
and check for uterine contractions.
Notify me if anything seems off.
Make sure to call me, okay?
- Have you been up all night?
- Yeah.
If you're unsure, ask the nurses.
Okay.
I'm heading to the operating room.
- I'm going to be alone?
- You want my company?
Gosh. No.
Ms. Lee Young-seon is
Professor Seo's patient.
Damn it. The Witch again?
Monitor her carefully. We're all dead
if we miss any deceleration.
I'm always stuck with Seo Jung-min.
Doctor!
There's no doctor here.
Doctor! Could you please come here?
There's no one here.
Doctor?
Yes, coming.
It's a little cold.
Damn it.
Of all the times,
why are you on vacation now?
To say it myself
would be too embarrassing.
No one cared when I mentioned your name.
The doctor in charge?
I see.
Okay.
Bye.
Doctor! One moment.
Over here.
So…
Here.
Doctor.
Thank you so much.
NOT THE SAME BOYFRIEND AS BEFORE
Look…
It's my second time.
But it's a secret.
Okay. I understand.
Honey.
Honey!
Gosh, I'm…
I'm so scared.
I don't know how others
can give birth so smoothly.
What am I going to do?
I'm really nervous too.
Doctor, will we be expecting soon?
Is the baby okay?
Well, she's not dilated at all yet.
The process would be faster
if this was her second or third time…
But it's her first.
So it might take more time.
Let me ask the professor,
and I'll get back to you.
Thank you, Doctor.
Thank you.
Also, if she's had a C-section before…
or a natural birth…
Then things might be different.
But since this is her first delivery,
please let me know
if she's in a lot of pain.
Okay, thank you.
Thank you.
Wait, Doctor.
Are you done?
Yeah. Eat up.
What a weird fellow.
I only notified 30 minutes late.
Why chew me out for it?
And who goes on vacation in March anyway?
You might as well
just eat with your hands.
Who bought this?
A patient's husband
gave it to me as a thank you.
What's there to thank
a lowly first-year for?
Are you sure it wasn't for a professor?
What did you do today?
Did you do something special?
Nothing much. Just what I was told to do.
I see.
I guess you were lucky then.
Guys, can I ask you something?
Ask away. I'll tell you everything.
She's a recurrent ovarian cancer patient,
but she won't sign
the surgical consent form.
How do I persuade her?
Pass it to a senior resident.
That's what they're there for.
I should still try to solve it myself.
Here!
Ask Prof. Ryu Jae-hui if it's related
to recurrent ovarian cancer.
That's not something
I can ask a professor about.
That'll hurt my pride.
I've asked him 16 times.
Hey, has it been 30 minutes?
Urine. I need to check her urine.
How disgusting.
What now?
Yes, Doctor?
Okay, I'll be right there. Goodbye.
Bye.
I'm on OB duty right now.
Hello?
I have to do that?
Okay, I'll be there.
This is it.
Ma'am.
This could be
very uncomfortable and painful.
Please excuse me.
Notify for active labor
if it's 4 cm or more.
Notify for full dilation
if it's totally dilated.
Check for amniotic sac ruptures.
What on earth?
Why? Why already?
Sorry?
She's…
She's all full.
FULL DILATION OF THE CERVIX
I'll call the professor.
She's suddenly all full so…
What did you say? She's what?
She's all full.
Ms. Lee Young-seon is at full dilation.
Hi, this is Seo Jung-min.
Get the current patient
out of the delivery room right now.
Another patient needs to give birth first.
An all-full patient
didn't receive an epidural,
but she's calm enough to ask how I'm doing
with a big smile on her face.
I'm sorry.
The only thing full here is my rage.
Ma'am, I just checked.
And you're only 2 cm dilated.
I see.
Let's wait a bit more.
Our first-year resident
must've been very eager to meet the baby.
She was too hasty.
March is really fun, isn't it?
Where did all the residents go?
Here's one.
No, I mean doctors.
Dr. Ku, this is unacceptable.
I'm sorry.
Take better care of the first-years.
Got that?
Yes, I understand.
Yes, Doctor?
You still haven't gotten it?
I'll go.
All those patients
had successful surgeries.
They're doing so well
after being discharged.
I know you're strong enough
to overcome this.
Did she sign it?
Yeah.
She must've been distraught
over the recurrence.
She just needed some time.
You were one step ahead of me.
I'd figured out how to get her to sign.
- There's a way to do that?
- Yes.
Berek & Hacker's Gynecologic Oncology.
It's in this book.
There's a chapter
called "Communication Skills."
"Remove any obstacles
between you and the patient."
"Sit at eye level
within an appropriate distance."
"And quickly offer tissues when they cry."
That's what you did.
I wanted to do the same
and get it signed quickly.
I didn't know that was in the book.
You were worried
she wouldn't get the surgery.
Well…
Darn it. I wanted to
get it signed under my name.
Too bad.
At least she's having the surgery.
That's good.
You're right, but…
If she'd signed it on the first day,
I wouldn't have wasted time
looking for this useless stuff.
I could've processed things more quickly.
I wanted to get all the consent forms
by 6:00 p.m. today
so I could notify the professor first.
- Sa-bi.
- Yes?
Are you trying to come in first place
at getting consent forms?
What's the point of that?
You can get praised at home or school
for coming in first place,
but this is a hospital.
Here, instead of your own desires,
it's where you put your patients first.
Even medical students know that.
But if you had to look it up
and still didn't understand,
it really was a waste of time.
See you.
Dr. Cha.
What is it?
It's Ms. Yeong Bo-mi in Room 1019.
Her urine output has been low
since this morning.
So?
There was significant blood loss
during yesterday's surgery,
and her urine is dark.
What was the urine output
in the last four hours?
Well…
I'll go check.
Around 80 cc.
It was about 20 cc per hour
during the early morning.
I wasn't really sure,
so I checked by the hour
from 4:00 a.m. to 3:00 p.m.
Her vitals were okay,
and the JP drain looked fine.
But I requested a CBC just in case.
Did you say from 4:00 a.m.?
Yes, ma'am.
In conclusion,
I think the patient is dehydrated.
I'm wondering
if fluid hydration would be a solution.
Do that then,
Dr. Um.
Yes, ma'am. Understood.
Where are you going now?
Let me explain it to her first!
Type up the prescription first, please…
Okay.
Nurse, I put in the prescription
for Ms. Yeong.
Okay.
FIRST-YEAR
FIRST-YEAR UM JAE-IL
Please tell me everything is fine.
Everything is fine.
In that case,
tell me everything will be fine as well.
I can't promise you that.
Who is it this time?
This seems really strange to me too.
She's all full. I think the baby's coming.
- Ma'am, please stay calm…
- I checked, and she's all full.
She's in pain too.
It's really different this time.
Doctor, it hurts too much!
Everyone's either
delivering babies or in surgery.
I'm the only one here.
But she's all full!
Are you sure?
You know what all full is, right?
I'm positive!
I can even see the baby's hair!
Can't you please come now?
If you're wrong again, Prof. Seo will…
That's what you're worried about?
Tell her to come right now!
Hurry!
Take her to the delivery room.
I'll be there in three minutes. Now.
Okay.
- We're moving to the delivery room.
- Okay.
Ma'am, breathe in short bursts.
Don't push.
Just hold on a little longer.
Doctor.
This is…
This is my first time,
so I don't really know, but…
This is really a first for me.
What?
Professor, Ms. Lee Young-seon
is all full and at Station 3.
You need to come right away.
I'm coming now.
But why didn't you call sooner?
I'm sorry. I missed it.
If it looks like the baby's coming,
handle the delivery in the meantime.
Yes, ma'am.
Hurry.
Hang in there, ma'am.
To Delivery Room 2, please.
Doctor, I think the baby is coming.
Not yet, ma'am.
I can't hold it in anymore!
No! Don't!
No! Hold on!
Stop! Gloves!
She delivered.
What's that sound?
That's not my patient's baby, right?
It's not, right?
This can't be happening, can it?
SURGERY IN PROGRESS
Sometimes, babies come out
quicker than expected.
But you hardly have any tears.
And the baby is crying well.
Everything is fine, so don't worry.
I see. I'm okay.
Congratulations.
I feel bad for making that doctor
go through such a hard time.
I'm sorry.
- Can you finish up here?
- Yes, Professor.
You did well, ma'am.
Thank you.
Dr. Oh Yi-young!
Here we are again.
I'm sorry.
My patient couldn't even
make it to the delivery room
and gave birth
in the middle of the hallway.
You see…
This wasn't her first baby,
so the labor came quicker--
It doesn't matter
if it was her first or not.
Even first-timers can go
into labor quickly
in rapid labor conditions.
Babies can come out suddenly,
unexpectedly, and at any given time.
Don't you know that?
Do you know what your mistake was today?
I made two big mistakes.
First,
I didn't monitor the patient carefully
since she was only 2 cm dilated.
Second,
I failed to monitor progress,
so I missed the active labor phase
and couldn't predict the time of delivery.
Those were my two biggest mistakes.
At least you know.
I'm sorry.
Be sure to go
and say a prayer of thanks today.
For what?
For the mother and her baby being okay.
Okay.
Make one more mistake.
Then…
I'll show you
what the real Witch looks like.
FIRST-YEAR RESIDENT LOUNGE
OB-GYN
Today's tarot reading was terrible.
Tomorrow's horoscope is awful too.
Does anyone have a power bank?
Here you go.
Look at you, Um Jae-il.
I feel drained too.
How could I not be?
My input and output are both at zero.
An electrolyte imbalance.
You had cake earlier.
So your input isn't at zero.
I don't know about your output though.
It's just an expression.
And I had that cake
ages ago.
AI programs show more warmth than you do.
They said we can go home now.
Yes!
I doubt you'll get
any sleep tonight, Yi-young.
They say you weep and think
of your mom on your first delivery.
Our fellow interns would call
their moms right after delivery.
Did you call yours too?
No, I couldn't.
For an experienced patient
to go from 2 cm to full dilation,
it takes three to four hours.
So why did it progress so quickly?
Were there risk factors for rapid labor?
That's what you're curious about?
Did the baby really feel slippery
as if you might drop it?
I don't know.
All I did was hold my hands out.
Right?
Honestly, you can't say
she delivered the baby.
It just came out.
You can't count that as her first.
Of course, it does.
I'm jealous. Congratulations, Yi-young.
Right. See you tomorrow.
Hey.
Still, doesn't it feel better
to struggle together than alone?
That's exactly why I didn't go solo.
I'm meant to be in a group. So--
- Can this wait until tomorrow?
- Hear me out for a second.
I discovered something really amazing.
Check this out.
There's an O in Oh Yi-young.
There's a B in Kim Sa-bi.
There's a G in Pyo Nam-kyung.
I spell it with a K.
And I'm Um Jay.
There's a Y in Jay.
As in OB-GYN.
Totally mind-blowing.
Isn't that incredible?
I guess not.
Fine.
I'm so hungry.
You haven't eaten, right?
Aren't you starving?
Want to grab dinner before we go?
- I have plans--
- I'm busy--
- Next time.
Sure. Let's eat next time.
- I have plans too.
- I see.
- See you tomorrow.
- Bye.
- Thanks.
- Sure.
Bye.
My goodness.
She's running.
What's gotten into her?
I've never seen Yi-young run before.
She woke up on her own this morning.
Oh, no. I think she's late.
That never bothered her before.
You're right about that.
They say you mature
after delivering a baby.
- I guess it's true.
- You know what Do-won said?
He wouldn't have chosen OB-GYN
if he hadn't seen a delivery as an intern.
Really?
Does that mean Yi-young
will become a doctor like him?
That may be a bit difficult.
Right?
Yi-young is a really transparent kid.
I can always read her face.
She seems totally into OB-GYN work now.
I think she'll really settle down
this time around.
It's only been three days.
I don't know if she'll last forever.
But I'm sure she'll have
the common decency to last for a month.
Gosh. Just a month?
You probably didn't hear about this
since you were on vacation.
It's a legendary story of a baby's birth.
Our first-year resident here
delivered a baby in the hallway.
I see. It was you.
- Yes.
- Prof. Seo must've chewed you out.
Well, first-years can make mistakes.
Gosh, Jung-min always had a nasty temper.
Everyone who witnesses
a delivery for the first time says,
"Professor, I think OB is my calling."
They all say that.
Really?
You're not interested, Dr. Oh?
Not really.
I guess it's still
a bit too early to know.
I don't let just anyone do this, you know.
But since today's surgery went well
and to celebrate your first delivery,
why don't you do the last suture?
That's okay, ma'am.
I see. Is it because you're scared?
I'll be here watching. It's okay.
I'm okay. Really.
I'll… I'll do it next time.
Is she serious?
It's a joke.
She's just kidding, Doctor.
Professor, I'll finish up.
You can leave it to me and get some rest.
Good work.
Thank you.
- Good work today.
- Thank you.
Excuse me.
Yes?
What was the name
of that first-year resident?
Dr. Oh Yi-young.
I see. Oh Yi-young.
So that's her name.
Good work today.
Yes, you too.
THANKS TO OUR SPECIAL GUEST, RA MI-RAN,
SSANGMUN'S OWN CHEETAH LADY
RESIDENT PLAYBOOK
The warning signs
have been showing for a while.
The residents' escape and escaping.
I may be broke, but I still have my pride.
I don't think
you're cut out to be a doctor.
They're all the same.
Please, just this once.
Look, Dr. First-Year. This isn't right.
Use your head.
Why do patients keep complaining
about the dressings?
- Well…
- What is it?
Hey! How will you manage as a doctor?
Is this what you call
being "in the doghouse"?
You're quitting as a doctor?
Why do you do your job like such a fool?
What did you say?
Let's not lie to each other from now on.
It's just that things go wrong
whenever she's involved.
Say it.
By the way, they're your own patients.
How do you not know them?
You're an enemy, not a colleague.
Yi-young, you're 50 million in debt.
Don't forget that.
How about you try something else?
I don't think I can be a doctor.
Tell her to handle it herself.
I can't do this anymore.
What am I doing here?
It's the perfect weather for running away.
Subtitle translation by: Sooji Kim